Let's talk about using subtitles when
you're learning English. So, you can
probably already notice that this video
has subtitles. This isn't something that
I have been doing recently. I've been
making videos without subtitles, but I'm
going to start creating videos with
subtitles um that are AI generated. So,
I pay to have this tool that can do this
for me. So, it might not be 100% correct
all the time, but uh I'm hoping it will
be like 97 98% correct, 99% perhaps. So,
uh I uh hope that you like this. I'm
going to talk about why I'm doing this
and I want to talk about using subtitles
in general. Okay. So, first of all, why
am I doing this? Why am I starting to
make videos with subtitles again? Well,
first of all, many people ask for
subtitles and yes, there is the YouTube
generated the automatic uh subtitles uh
from YouTube. Um but for some reason, a
lot of people just don't like this or
they don't want to click on the little
button uh and choose the language and
all of that. So, uh, a lot of people,
uh, don't like that or they just don't
trust YouTube autogenerated subtitles.
Um, honestly, they're pretty good. So,
uh, you can try them out on other videos
that don't have subtitles and, uh, you
can see for yourself. I find that
they're pretty good. Uh, but many people
prefer to have the subtitles on the
screen and so uh that's why I'm doing
this. Uh, you know, people have
expressed that they really like the long
videos that I've done for the past I
don't know how long it's been, but I've
been doing them for a while. Um, and
these are the videos that uh people get
more excited about because they can see
my face. Uh, people like seeing me for
some reason and uh they get more views
when I first publish them. But really,
the videos that I've made that have
helped the most people, it seems, are my
videos with subtitles dedicated to
different levels, like A1, A2, B1. Those
listening videos, they still get tons
and tons of views. Not all of them, but
uh the older ones still generate uh many
views over the months and years. Uh some
of them have in the millions actually,
not many of them, but a few of them. So,
uh those seem to be the videos that
really uh help the most people. Uh even
though some people they don't need the
subtitles
uh they don't want uh the subtitles uh
the thing is if you don't want the
subtitles you can simply ignore them. Uh
that's uh something that's possible even
though you think that uh having them on
the screen distracts you. Maybe that
might be true for some of you. Uh, but I
can't please everyone. There will always
be some people that aren't completely
satisfied with the choices I make in
terms of how I make my videos. Um, but I
figured that I should start using these
subtitles so that uh all the people that
need subtitles can have them. And
hopefully the people that don't want
them can simply cover them up, put
something there to cover them, uh, or
just not look at them. Uh, that's
probably the easiest thing uh, to do.
And uh I've watched videos where I put
the subtitles on, but I don't look at
them unless I need them, unless I don't
understand something. It's possible,
folks. So, uh hopefully this will be the
best solution for uh my videos in the
future to reach more people, help more
people, and uh hopefully you guys still
uh enjoy these types of videos. I think
I'm going to make them a little shorter.
Uh possibly 15 minutes or so. And I
don't know what I'll talk about yet. Uh
maybe uh mostly language learning stuff,
possibly some other things. Um but
regardless of the topic, the goal is
still to provide interesting content for
you to practice your listening. And I'm
showing my face so you can see me.
People really like this format. So, uh,
I'm going to continue to do it like
this. I think I could change obviously,
but uh, I'll probably, uh, make videos
like this one. And let me know if you
like this type of uh subtitling where it
kind of shows you which word I'm saying
in the moment. Um I think most people
like that.
it kind of helps them uh follow along
better. But um I'm sure uh with the tool
I'm using, there might be options uh
where it doesn't do that where it just
shows the words and it doesn't show you
where I am in the phrase or whatever.
So, let me know. Uh leave a comment down
below and tell me what you think about
these subtitles. And I'm sure some of
you will comment and say you don't like
having subtitles on the video. I'm
sorry. Again, I can't please everyone.
Um, I would just say that you can try to
cover them or not look at them. I've
done this plenty of times. It's
possible. So, uh, how should you use
subtitles when learning English?
Well, uh, let me talk in general, not
just about my content, but in general.
Uh, first of all, a great way to do this
is to repeat the video multiple times.
Um, the way that I've, uh, talked about
the most, I think, is watching the video
the first time without the subtitles to
see how much you can understand. And
then you watch the second time with the
subtitles so you can see uh which words
you didn't get. Uh and then the third
time without subtitles to try to
understand everything this time without
reading them. So, uh you can do it that
way or perhaps you just listen or watch
twice. Uh the first time with the
subtitles just to try to get everything
and then the second time without
subtitles to try to get everything
without seeing the words. So, uh you can
do this in a number of ways, but the
goal is to uh eventually understand the
video without the subtitles. Okay? So,
with a video like this one, uh you would
watch it maybe not looking at the
subtitles, just looking at my face, and
then the second time looking at the
subtitles, and the third time looking at
my face again. or cover the subtitles if
you prefer. Um, you can do it that way.
If there's a video that uh doesn't have
subtitles on YouTube, you can uh use the
YouTube autogenerated subtitles. They
work. Uh I I use them. Uh so uh you can
watch uh without the subtitles and then
activate those subtitles and then uh
turn them off again however you want.
But uh using repetition is a good way to
practice your listening and see what you
can understand, what was hard for you to
understand, and then eventually
understand everything without the
subtitles. So, uh that's uh one tip.
Another tip is uh that you can just look
at the subtitles when you can't
understand a word. I like this uh tip
here. like you can watch this video and
just look at my face and when I say
something that's not completely clear uh
to you or maybe there's a phrase or a
word I use that you're not familiar
with, then you look down and you see
what it is that I said. And that's a
great way to use them. And uh it's
pretty simple and it helps you train
without subtitles, but then use the
subtitles to help you uh get what you
couldn't understand or um see u the new
word that I used, etc. Right? That's a
great way to use them. Uh you can also
use subtitles for I guess I'll call it
targeted listening practice. So uh you
notice which patterns you can't
understand. Let me explain this. If you
can understand something when it's
written down, but you can't understand
it when you just hear it without seeing
it, that means that uh you know the word
or you know the phrase, but you can't
understand it. Well, it's not a new
phrase for you, but you can't understand
it. Um, this means that you have a good
opportunity to see what the difference
is between what you're expecting to hear
and how native speakers actually say the
phrase. Okay? So when you use subtitles,
uh for example, you can watch without
looking at the subtitles and then you
can't understand something and then you
look down and you say, "Huh, why
couldn't I understand that? I know that
phrase." Um, and then you repeat, you
rewind the video and you train with that
uh phrase. you uh listen multiple times
to see how a native speaker actually
says that phrase. So, you're targeting
the things that you can't understand and
then seeing why you couldn't understand
it, what you were expecting to hear, and
then you see how it really sounds. So
that can help you notice and better
understand different patterns in
English. So that's something uh that
could be useful for you. You can do the
same thing for pronunciation practice.
So, uh, when that happens, you can, uh,
like I said, rewind the video, um, watch
it again, listen, uh, multiple times to
hear how a native speaker says it, and
then you can replicate that with your
own, uh, you know, saying it yourself.
So, you practice your listening and your
pronunciation. In that way, you are uh
noticing how things really sound and
then you try to say it the way that
native speakers say it. So, this can be
good for listening and pronunciation.
And then lastly, you can use subtitles
when you're just watching content for
pleasure. Let's say it's the end of the
day. You want to watch uh something for
entertainment and instead of watching
the show in your own language or the
video in your own language, you watch it
in English. And uh this can be hard, but
if you put the subtitles on, you can uh
understand it much better probably. And
during this time, if you're just
watching something for pleasure after a
long day of work, then you probably just
want to watch it and not rewind it and
take all these notes and things like
that. You just watch the content, but
you have the subtitles on and um you're
practicing in that way. um you probably
won't understand everything, but the
subtitles will make it easier for you to
just enjoy uh that show, that video or
whatever. And so in that case, uh
there's nothing you should really do.
You should just relax and enjoy it. but
you're getting some English practice and
because of the subtitles, you might be
able to understand enough to just enjoy
the show or enjoy the video or whatever
it is. So, that's another thing that you
can do. All right, I hope that you liked
this format of video with the subtitles.
Um, leave a comment down below and let
me know if this style of subtitles uh is
good or whatever. I don't know exactly
uh what I'm going to be doing and
talking about. And I assume, like I
said, I'll just make videos that are
like this, a little shorter than I've
been making them recently, but with
subtitles. Um, and uh I don't know what
I'll title these videos. maybe
intermediate uh English listening
practice or I don't know. Um but we'll
see. I just wanted to make a video
talking about subtitles to introduce
this new era of videos that I hope to
make and to give you some tips. And of
course, as always, remember to check out
my advanced podcast episodes in which I
speak fast. And check out my US
Conversations podcast in which I talk to
different people from around the
country. It's a lot of fun and it's
great practice for you because you
practice with my authentic conversations
that I have with other native speakers.
So, both of those links are down below.
All right, thank you for watching this
video and I'll talk to you in the next